American Council of Learned Societies. Committee on Native American Languages. 1882-1958 Mss.497.3.B63c
American Philosophical Society
- Otomi
  - Grammatical sketch of Otomi, n.d., 1912-1950; TMs and AMs, 28L.; Radin, Paul, 1883-1959
    Sketch of Toluca dialect, checked with a San Pablo Otomi. The author made changes in the text after 1950. The original is or microfilm. Intended as the beginning of Radin, Otomi-English dictionary, No. 2618 below.
    Freeman and Smith 2617
  - Otomi-English dic tionary, n.d., -1950; AMs, 41L.; Radin, Paul, 1883-1959
    Continuation of grammatical sketch..., No. 2617 above. 660 Otomi (Toluca dialect) forms with English equivalents. Some corrections made by the author after 1950. The original is on microfilm
    Freeman and Smith 2618
  - Sintesis de la discusion en el consejo de lenguas indB!genas sobre el alfabeto Otomi, 1939; TMs, 11 l.; Council of Native Languages
    In Spanish. Report of discussion in Mexico City of Council of Native Languages in May, 1939, on an Otomi alphabet. Includes material on phonetics, symbols, as well as minority opinion and objections
    Freeman and Smith 2620
  - Otomi vocabulary, 1915; AMs, 2 slips; Sapir, Edward, 1884-1939
    In Otomi-English. Vocabulary list of 26 items.
    Freeman and Smith 2619
- Ottawa
  - Ottawa Indian manuscripts, 1947; TMs and A.D, 150 l.; Ettawageshik, Jane Willets, 1915-1996
    Manuscript for material recorded No. 2842, written in Ottawa by Chief Ettawageshik. Interlinear translations. Word lists made from manuscripts by Miss Willets. Typescript, c.c., of manuscript. Contains Nanabojo myths; legends; interview on history of Ottawa. Table of contents. Vocabulary cards.
    Freeman and Smith 2641
  - Ottawa Indian songs and dances; musical score, 1954; AMs, 7p. 11 songs.; Hunkins, Eusebia Simpson
    Songs including naming chant by Fred Ettawageshik; transcribed from recordings made by Jane Willets Ettawageshik.
    Freeman and Smith 2621
    Donor, Eusebia Hunkins, 1954.
- Paiute
  - Field notes on Kaibab Paiute, Linguistic and ethnologic, 1910; TMs Cy, 194L.; Sapir, Edward, 1884-1939
    Paiute ethnographic notes: names of tribes, springs, illustrations of material culture, names of natural objects, life history, tribal history, manufactures, hunting. Vocabulary of reckoning of time. Paiute linguistic notes: vocabulary lists, body parts, numerals, counting nouns, and animalnames. Paradigms. Most items have English translation. Images include pencil sketches of utensils, dwellings, blankets, papoose.
    Freeman and Smith 2643
    Cf. Sapir (1930)
    Donor, Leslie Spier, Feb. 1957
    Microfilmed as: Film 372, reel 19-20
- Papago
  - Papago phonetics and texts, TMs part Cy, 10L.; Unidentified
    In Papago-English. Brief discussion of Papago phonetics; texts relating to hunting rabbit and deer, with interlinear and free translations. Songs and a speech.
    Freeman and Smith 2646
  - Papago vocabulary, 1940; TMs Cy and AMs, 2L.; Swadesh, Morris, 1909-1967
    In Spanish-Papago. Vocabulary list of 118 items.
    Freeman and Smith 2647
- Patwin
  - The Patwin language, 1929; TMs, 125L.; Angulo, Jaime de
    Contents: phonology and morphology; semasiology (semantically arranged vocabularies), conversation, and autobiography. Colusa dialect.
    Freeman and Smith 2650
  - Patwin-English dictionary, n.d., 1932?; AMs, 121L.; Radin, Paul, 1883-1959
    Freeman and Smith 2654
  - Patwin texts, 1932; AMs, 259p.; Radin, Paul, 1883-1959
    Ethnographic and folkloristic texts together with free translations and introduction. Obtained from an informant at Rumsey, Capay valley Tebti dialect. Radin had studied No. 2850 (Colusa) dialect. Some texts were read to the informant, who translated them into Patwin and are not, therefore, authentic.
    Freeman and Smith 2662
  - A sketch of Patwin grammar, n.d., ca. 1932-1959; AMs, 71p.; Radin, Paul, 1883-1959
    Table of contents; phonetics; general characteristics, verbs, nouns, suffixes, etc.
    Freeman and Smith 2663
    Cf. No. 2664 for rough draft of this document.
- Pawnee
  - Morphology of the Pawnee language, n.d.; T and AMs, 88L.; Weltfish, Gene
    Includes: outline for a Pawnee grammar (South Band dialect); partial treatment of verb morphology according to the plan of the outline.
    Freeman and Smith 4649
- Penutian
  - Coos-Takelma-Penutian comparisons, 1914; AMs, 14L.; Sapir, Edward, 1884-1939
    Original Sapir manuscript, revised in No. 2951 below.
    Freeman and Smith 2950
    Cf. description in Swadesh and Sapir (1953): 132-134.
    Donor, Morris Swadesh, 1952.
  - Coos-Takelma-Penutian comparisons, 1914; 1952; TMs Cy, 12L.; Swadesh, Morris, 1909-1967
    Sapir's original document in No. 2950 with modern phonemic orthography.
    Freeman and Smith 2951
    Printed, Sapir and Swadesh (1953)
    Donor, Morris Swadesh, 1952 (?)
  - Comparative Penutian glosses, 1909-1917; TMs, 19L.; Sapir, Edward, 1884-1939
    A compilation made by Morris Swadesh of marginal glosses in Sapir's copies of Frachtenberg (1913), (1914), and (1917); also, Boas (1910) and Dixon (1909).
    Freeman and Smith 2949
    Cf. Sapir and Swadesh (1953) and Sapir (1921a).
- Pima
  - Pima speeches, n.d.; TMs, 52L.; Herzog, George
    In Pima-English. 14 texts of speeches with interlinear translation; most of the speeches relate to rain making and warfare.
    Freeman and Smith 2961
- Pipil
  - Pipil notes, 1912?; AMs, 1 notebook. 13p.; Boas, Franz, 1858-1942
    In Pipil-Nauhuatl Spanish. Vocabulary and comparisons with Nahuatl; Spanish translations.
    This material has subsequently been identified as Pochutecan (Zapotec).
    Freeman and Smith 2962
- Pomo
  - The Pomo language, ca. 1935; AMs, 49L. and Cy; Angulo, Jaime de
    A succinct study, similar to No. 3018, intended for publication. Studies the language from the point of view of grammatical categories.
    Freeman and Smith 3013
  - Pomo semasiology, 1930-1935?; TMs, 32L.; Angulo, Jaime de
    Word lists arranged semantically, according to de Angulo and Freeland (1930b).
    Freeman and Smith 3014
  - The reminiscences of a Pomo chief, ca. 1935; AMs, 306L.; Angulo, Jaime de
    Autobiography of William Ralganal Benson, dictated in the Yukaya dialect; free transla tion; grammatical notes which refer to grammars, No. 3013 and No. 3016.
    Freeman and Smith 3015
    Microfilmed as: Film 372.5, reel 4
  - The Clear Lake dialect of the Pomo language in north-central California, 1920-1935; AMs part Cy, 219L.; Angulo, Jaime de
    A description based on study of grammatical categories rather than on parts of speech, like No. 3013. Includes note of de Angulo to Franz Boas, n.d., mentioning No. 3013.
    Freeman and Smith 3016
    Cf. de Angulo (1935) and No. 3015 for texts referred to in work.
- Potawatomi
  - Potawatomi vocabulary, 1937; TMs with MS. Additions, 12L.; Swadesh, Morris, 1909-1967
    220 English items with filled-in Potawatomi equivalents. 20 items in an unidentified language.
    Freeman and Smith 3020
- Pueblo
  - Report of field work conducted in the southwest, summer 1927, 1935; TMs, 3L.; Herzog, George
    Preliminary report on style and categories of Pueblo songs. Work done under Boas' guidance.
    Freeman and Smith 3075
- Pentlatch
  - Pentlatch materials, ca. 1890; AMs, 67L., 32p., 2 slips.; Boas, Franz, 1858-1942
    Includes English-Pentlatch vocabulary; Pentlatch-English vocabulary; Pentlatch vocabulary; texts with interlinear translation in German.
    Freeman and Smith 3090
    Microfilmed as: Film 372, 19
- Puyallup
  - Puyallup texts, 1934; TMs part Cy, 307L.; Aginsky, Ethel Gertrude, 1910-
    Texts with MS. interlinear translation. 140p. Each text includes one or more pages giving analyses of new words. Morpheme boundaries are shown and morphs are identified by broad class labels and meaning, such as "prefix meaning time." Each text is followed by a free translation.
    Freeman and Smith 3091
- Quechua
  - Notes on Quechua language and proposed orthography, 1937; TMs, 27L.; Farfan, Jose M. B.
    In Spanish and English. 4 statements; also, covering letter of author to Franz Boas, April 24, 1937.
    Freeman and Smith 3151
  - The reaction of the evangelical missionaries ..., 1936; TMs, 3L.; Ritchie, John
    Discussion of missionary reaction to the proposed new Quechua orthography (see No. 3151 above).
    Freeman and Smith 3153
  - Observations ... concerning the Quechua orthography, 1936; TMs, 5L.; Shedd, Leslie M. and Carl H. Wintersteen
    Concerning the new orthography (see No. 3151 above).
    Freeman and Smith 3154
  - Ortografia, 1937; TMs Cy, 2L.; Ward, I. C.
    Discussion of new Quechua orthography (see No. 3151 above). Copy made by John Ritchie.
    Freeman and Smith 3157
- Quiche
  - Linguistic map of Chiapas, 1924; AMs, Map.; Schuller, Rudolph
    Document submitted (?)C:with Schuller (1924).
    Freeman and Smith 3173
    Maps.
- Quileute
  - Quileute grammar, 1928; TMs Cy, 20 L.; Andrade, Manuel José, 1885-1941
    Incomplete, antecedent to Andrade (1933). Contents: phonetics, suffixes, nominal suffixes, pronouns.
    Freeman and Smith 3188
    Donor, Norman A. McQuown (excepting nominal suffixes, already in collection), 1954.
  - Groups of words, collected by M. J. Andrade to illustrate the various types of accent in the Quileute language, 1928; TMs, 6L. 18slips.; Andrade, Manuel José, 1885-1941
    Words spoken into a dictaphone by a Quileute in Seattle. Contains "Remarks on Quileute dictaphone records" with musical notations and graphic forms (forms published).
    Freeman and Smith 3184
    Cf. Andrade (1933): 164-165.
    Donor (of copies 2 and 3), Norman A McQuown, 1954
  - Quileute vocabulary, 1928; AMs, Ca.2,650 cards.; Andrade, Manuel José, 1885-1941
    File boxes arranged phonetically. Quileute notes on 20 cards.
    Freeman and Smith 3192
    Donor, Department of Anthropology, Univ of Chicago, 1950
    Microfilmed as: Film 372.7, reel 26
  - Quileute grammar, ca. 1930; AMs, Ca.2,000 slips and cards.; Andrade, Manuel José, 1885-1941
    Notes probably used in preparing the author's "Quileute Grammar, " (1933).
    Freeman and Smith 3189
    Donor, Department of Anthropology, University of Chicago, 1950
  - Quileute ethnology: Lapush, Washington, 1916; AMs and TMs, 5 notebooks. 84L.; Frachtenberg, Leo Joachim, 1883-1930
    Field notebooks and typed transcript of 4, no. 4, 5, 7, and 8. Cf. typescript of same in No. 3178. Mental and physical traits, population, basketry, matting, early history and distribution, manufactures, houses and households, clothing and adornments, subsistence, travel..., trade, fishing, warfare, games and pastimes, sign language, social organization and festivals, birth-childhood, religion, guardian spirits, shamanism, ceremonials, ethical concepts and teaching, medicine, current beliefs, art, and text "Origin of Potlatch."
    Freeman and Smith 3177
    Donor (of vol 6), Norman A McQuown, 1954
    Microfilmed as: Film 372.1, reel 52
  - Quileute ethnology notes, 1928; AMs, 1 notebook 22p.; Andrade, Manuel José, 1885-1941
    Freeman and Smith 3174
    Donor, Norman A McQuown, December, 1954
  - The ceremonial societies of the Quileute Indians, 1916; TMs Cy, 56L.; Frachtenberg, Leo Joachim, 1883-1930
    Incomplete:p. 1-32, 45-56. Apparently based on notebook 6 of No. 3177, but prepared for general use.
    Freeman and Smith 3175
    Donor, Norman A McQuown, 1954
  - Quileute ethnology, 1915-1916; TMs, 6L., 1 map.; Frachtenberg, Leo Joachim, 1883-1930
    History, numbers, and location of the Quileute; a different typescript of part of No. 3178 (from notebook 2:1-2:12). Also, a second copy, lacking map.
    Freeman and Smith 3176
  - Quileute ethnology: Lapush, Washington, 1916; TMs, 275L. and illus.; Frachtenberg, Leo Joachim, 1883-1930
    Typed transcripts of notebooks 1-5 and 7 of Frachtenberg's field notebooks. Original notebooks of 4, 5, 7, and typescript in No. 3177. Copy of 2:1-2:12 in No. 3176. See 3177 for general contents.
    Freeman and Smith 3178
    Microfilmed as: Film 372.1, reel 52-53
  - Quileute ethnology, 1908-1913; TMs Cy, 18L. and 130 plates.; Reagan, Albert B.
    Materials sent by teacher and missionary to Edward Sapir, ethnologist for Canada Department of Mines. Quillayute myths appar entry checked by L. J. Frachtenberg against the memory of his informant, Arthur Howeattle. Also, the airship "tomanawis" canoe and medicine actors; Dr. Lester or He-tucthal-took of the Quillayutes; some notes on the Quillayute Indians, Washington. 130 drawings made by Quileute school children and by Reagan. MS. endorsements by E. Sapir and L. J. Frachtenberg. Images include pencil and ink sketches, color crayon drawings, watercolors, and geletin silver prints of utensils, canoes, drums, rattles, toys, arrows, masks, totems, decorative patterns.
    Freeman and Smith 3180
    Drawings.; Gelatin silver prints; Sketches.; Watercolors
    - Quileute men with masks, 1908-1913
    - Tc'awe'tcil, 1908-1913
  - Quileute songs, 1922 (1917); AMs, 2 notebooks.; Frachtenberg, Leo Joachim, 1883-1930
    Recordings made in 1917 at Lapush, Washington. The field notebooks give names of songs and their owners, performers, words of songs with translation, except for dance songs.
    Freeman and Smith 3179
  - English Quileute vocabulary, 1928; TMs Cy with ms. Additions, 104L.; Andrade, Manuel José, 1885-1941
    Alphabetical by English; reverse of No. 3187. 1, 100 items.
    Freeman and Smith 3183
    Donor, Norman A McOuown, 1954
  - Quileute English vocabulary, 1928; TMs Cy with ms. Additions, 22L.; Andrade, Manuel José, 1885-1941
    ca.1, 100 items, alphabetical by Quileute; reverse of No. 3183. A second copy "General vocabulary."
    Freeman and Smith 3187
    Donor, Norman A McQuown, December 1954
  - Notes on the English-Quileute vocabulary, 1928?; AMs, 17L., in notebook.; Andrade, Manuel José, 1885-1941
    3p. of notes; textual material.
    Freeman and Smith 3186
  - Quileute words and sentences, and phonetic observations, 1928?; AMs, 90p, in notebook.; Andrade, Manuel José, 1885-1941
    Examples of sentences, including interrogative form and word building, etc. Phonetic observations.
    Freeman and Smith 3195
  - Interrelations of pitch, stress, and quantity in Quileute, 1928?; TMs Cy, 4L.; Andrade, Manuel José, 1885-1941
    Copy of unpublished article. A revision is subsumed in Andrade (1933).
    Freeman and Smith 3185
  - Quileute word lists, grouped by accents, 1928?; AMs, 11L. in notebook. 8 slips.; Andrade, Manuel José, 1885-1941
    Words grouped according to accentual patterns.
    Freeman and Smith 3194
  - Quileute (?) vocabulary, 1928?; AMs, 13L. 55 cards.; Andrade, Manuel José, 1885-1941
    Examples of words and phrases, including possessives. Mostly English only, with reference number.
    Freeman and Smith 3193
  - Quileute grammatical notes, 1915; AMs, 1 notebook. 73p.; George, Hallie B. and Leo Joachim Frachtenberg, 1883-1930
    Frachtenberg's notes made with the aid of George, an English-speaking Quileute Indian. Brief addition in 1916 with aid of Arthur Howeattle.
    Freeman and Smith 3197
  - Quileute morphology, ca. 1933; AMs, 42p.; Andrade, Manuel José, 1885-1941
    Word lists of Quileute forms with English translations, including nominal classifiers, verbs, numerals. Contains tables of vowels and pronouns which were published in Andrade (1933).
    Freeman and Smith 3190
  - An analysis of the Quileute language, 1929; TMs, with MS. additions., 258L.; Andrade, Manuel José, 1885-1941
    Original MS. for Andrade (1933), together with carbons of other title pages and a preface not used in published version.
    Freeman and Smith 3181
    Printed, Andrade (1933).
  - Quileute texts, 1922; AMs, 1 notebook. 47p.; Frachtenberg, Leo Joachim, 1883-1930
    Unpublished texts, sequel to Andrade (1931); partial interlinear translations. Vol. 15 of field notebooks.
    Freeman and Smith 3196
  - Quileute texts, 1928; TMs and AMs, 2 note books and 32p.; Andrade, Manuel José, 1885-1941
    Texts with notes and some interlinear translation; also, list of texts 1-45, collected by L. J. Frachtenberg, 1915-1916.
    Freeman and Smith 3191
    Printed, Andrade (1931), pt. 1: no. 2-26.
- Quinault
  - Quinault ethnographic and field notes, 1897; AMs, 15 notebooks.; Farrand, Livingston, 1867-1939
    Folkloristic texts in English (Quinault and Nez Percé). Texts in Quinault with interlinear translations; scraps and accounts; paradigms and vocabularies. 5p. of an Athabas can vocabulary.
    Freeman and Smith 3198
    Microfilmed as: Film 372.1, reel 48-49
  - Quinault vocabulary and paradigms, 1916-1917; AMs, 54L.; Teit, James Alexander, 1864-1922
    Vocabulary includes parts of body, natural objects, implements, mammals, fish, reptiles. Letter from Teit to Boas, Sept. 15, 1916; accounts for work on Flathead and Salish MSS.
    Freeman and Smith 3199
- Salish
  - The Middle Columbia Salish, 1910; TMs Cy, 90p.; Teit, James Alexander, 1864-1922
    Incomplete ethnographic manuscript. See No. 3205.
    Freeman and Smith 3204
    Printed, Teit (1928).
  - Salish ethnographic notes, 1911-1917; TMs and AMs, 265L.; Teit, James Alexander, 1864-1922
    Lists of Salish artifacts sent to museums: interior Salish basketry to Victoria Museum; Lillooet materials to American Museum of Natural History; Shuswap and Ntlakyapamuk materials to same; geological specimens to Geological Survey of Canada; basketry and clothing to same; materials to Field Museum; materials to Provincial Museum. Also, note of Edward Sapir to Teit, June 1913, enclosing typed copy of Thompson River materials sent to Geological Survey of Canada. Images include pencil sketches of clothing, utensils, decorative patterns, arrowheads, bowls, drums, shoes.
    Freeman and Smith 3206
  - Comparative vocabularies of eight Salishan languages, 1900; AMs, 18L.; Boas, Franz, 1858-1942
    532 alphabetically arranged English items with equivalents in one or more of the following: LkuC1gen, Nanaimo, Squamish, Sisiatl, Satlolk (Comer), Pentlatch, Bilhula (Bella Coola), Ntlakyapamuk (Thompson).
    Freeman and Smith 3210
  - Comparative Salishan vocabularies, 1925; AMs, 1628 strips of paper.; Boas, Franz, 1858-1942
    Parallel vocabulary lists in 35 Salish languages. 1,195 columns identified by English word at top; words are semantically arranged. Also, index, index slips, and miscellaneous comparisons.
    Freeman and Smith 3209
    Cf. punch cards based on these items in No. 3217 below.
  - Salish tribal names and distributions, 1907-1910; AMs and TMs, 125L., 5 slips, 3 maps, 2 notebooks.; Teit, James Alexander, 1864-1922
    Field notebooks with data on tribal nem-s, traditional location, basketry, customs of British Columbia Salish. Notes to Eva Emery Dy (1900); maps showing locations and place names. Letters of Franz Boas to James A. Teit: Aug. 9, 1912 and Jan. 18, 1913, requesting information on basketry. Extracts from Teit letters, 1909-1910, in hand of Lucy Kramer: Salish historical and linguistic observations. 4 typescripts: tribal names of Interior Salish; names for tribes in sign language; additional information on former distribution of Salish tribes along Columbia River to the south; linguistics.
    Freeman and Smith 3207
  - Salishan comparative vocabularies, n.d.; AMs and TMs, 117L. and 5 slips.; Teit, James Alexander, 1864-1922
    Vocabularies of Interior and Coastal Salish; notes; index (with c.c.). The items are similarly arranged, numbered 1-62 for Interior and 1-897 for Coast. Also, discussion of Interior Salish languages and suffix comparisons.
    Freeman and Smith 3220
  - Miscellaneous Interior Salishan materials, 1909; AMs, 185 p., 39 slips.; Teit, James Alexander, 1864-1922
    Miscellaneous grammatical materials and several comparative vocabularies. Image includes ink sketch of "salehenko club".
    Freeman and Smith 3219
  - Songs from the Salish area, 1915-1921; AMs and TMs, 34L., 58p., 7 slips.; Teit, James Alexander, 1864-1922
    Notes on ca. 80 songs as to provenance, informants, cultural context. Typescript of texts with translations. Thompson, Shuswap, Lillooet, and Okanagon among the Salish; also Athabascan and Cree. Collected for and sent to National Museum of Canada, Ottawa.
    Freeman and Smith 3208
  - Salish ethnographic materials, 1908-1920; AMs and TMs, 470p., 50 slips, 1 notebook, 55 plates.; Teit, James Alexander, 1864-1922
    Contains data on tribal names; personal names; basketry, tattooing and clothing, with drawings; folkloristic texts in English. Ethnographic notes, drawings, description of museum specimens. "Notes on the Snake Indians." Historical notes based on tradition and various printed works. Images include ink and pencil sketches of canoes, decorative patterns, traps, facial tattoos.
    Freeman and Smith 3205
    Some of the plates were printed in Teit (1930a). Texts printed as Teit (1937).
    - Luke Shona-mitza (chief), 1908-1920
    - Tsila-ghesket, patriarch of the N-kam-chin band of Indians, 1908-1920
  - Salishan dialects, 1920; TMs, 12L.; Boas, Franz, 1858-1942, Herman K. Haeberlin, and James A. Teit
    Data relating to the Salish languages, their distribution, and the distributions of neighboring languages.
    Freeman and Smith 3211
  - Salish vocabulary: comparison on coded punch cards, 1950; AMs and TMs, 167 cards.; Swadesh, Morris, 1909-1967
    Each card represents one vocabulary item taken from Boas' comparative Salish vocabularies, No. 3209. Guide card shows placement of the languages on the punch cards.
    Freeman and Smith 3217
  - Salish internal relationships, 1950; TMs Cy, 24L.; Swadesh, Morris, 1909-1967
    Study of affinities among Salishan languages, based on vocabulary correspondences. Inferences are drawn as to prehistory.
    Freeman and Smith 3216
    Printed, Swadesh (1950).
  - Salishan comparative phonology, 1951-1952; TMs, 45L., 5 maps.; Swadesh, Morris, 1909-1967
    A lengthy study of relationship, distribution, structure, and phonologies.
    Freeman and Smith 3215
    Printed, substantially revised, as Swadesh (195C:26).
  - Salish cognates, 1951; AMs and TMs, 215L.; Swadesh, Morris, 1909-1967
    Ca. 200 cognate sets from various Salish languages, taken primarily from Boas' comparative vocabularies, No. 3209, with orthography changed to interpret the original phonemically. Other sources explained in a note.
    Freeman and Smith 3214
  - Notes on Salish inflections, ca. 1910; AMs, 1 notebook.; Boas, Franz, 1858-1942
    Salish notes, based on Mengarini's Grammar.
    Freeman and Smith 3202
    Cf. Mengarini (1881).
  - Kalispel and Salish vocabulary, ca. 1910; AMs, 32p. 6L.; Teit, James Alexander, 1864-1922
    Field notes; word lists of Kalispel, Salish, Pend'Oreille, Flathead.
    Freeman and Smith 3218
  - Salish and Wakashan, 1915; AMs, 26 cards.; Sapir, Edward, 1884-1939
    Lexical comparisons.
    Freeman and Smith 3213
    Printed as Sapir (1949).
    Donor, Morris Swadesh, 1952
- San Felipe (Popolocan)
  - San Felipe word list, 1920; AMs, 1 notebook. 66p.; Boas, Franz, 1858-1942
    Word lists, paradigms, texts.
    Freeman and Smith 3221
- Sanpoil (Okanagan)
  - Sanpoil notes, n.d.; TMs, 10L. 9 photos.; Gould, Marian K.
    Contains data on social organization, tanning, tipi, fish traps, foods, stone implements. Images include photographs of drawings by Karneecher of tanning, hunting buffalo, tools, traps, and dwellings.
    Freeman and Smith 3224
    Drawings.; Gelatin silver prints
- Santo Domingo
  - Santo Domingo word list, 1920; AMs, 1 notebook. 71p.; Boas, Franz, 1858-1942
    Word lists and paradigms.
    Freeman and Smith 3225
- Sarsi
  - Sarsi linguistics, 1922, n.d.; AMs, 7 notebooks of ca. 100p. ea.; Sapir, Edward, 1884-1939, coll.
    Includes: vocabulary; paradigms; texts with notes; English translations.
    Freeman and Smith 4707
    Cf: no. 4708.
    Donor, Harry Hoijer, Jan 1973
- Sisiatl (Seechelt)